Guide to the Patricia A. Etter Research Files for California Odyssey
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Patricia A. Etter Research Files for California Odyssey
2001-2011
WA MSS S-3137
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.63
2 boxes
Research files for the publication of William R. Goulding's journal documenting his 1849 journey to California, California Odyssey. Includes subject files pertaining to Goulding and his work as a physician, Etter's correspondence with coeditor Howard Lamar and Warwick Goulding, maps pertaining to and photographs of Goulding, and a computer disk of notes on and photographs of Goulding.
Etter, Patricia A., 1932-2013
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Box 2 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Patricia A. Etter, 2011.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Subject Files, 2001-2011. II. Correspondence, 2007-2011. III. Maps and Photographs, 2007-2008. IV. Restricted Fragile Papers.
Biographical / Historical
Patricia A. Etter (1932-2013), librarian, historian of the American west, and editor of William R. Goulding's journal, California Odyssey.
Scope and Contents
Research files for the publication of William R. Goulding's journal documenting his 1849 journey to California, California Odyssey. Includes subject files pertaining to Goulding and his work as a physician, Etter's correspondence with coeditor Howard Lamar and Warwick Goulding, maps pertaining to and photographs of Goulding, and a computer disk of notes on and photographs of Goulding.
Overland journeys to the Pacific; Physicians -- West (U.S.); California -- Gold discoveries; West (U.S.) -- Description and travel; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Physicians -- West (U.S.) -- 19th century; Overland journeys to the Pacific -- 1849; Etter, Patricia A., 1932-2013; Goulding, Warwick; Goulding, William R. (William Robinson), 1806-1865; Goulding, William R. (William Robinson), 1806-1865 ( California odyssey); Lamar, Howard Roberts, 1923-
- Subject Files, 2001-2011; Series I
  - Arizona History journal, 2011 (Box 1)
  - Army Medical Museum (National Museum of Health and Medicine), 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Douglas Hospital, Washington, D.C., 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - Lincoln Hospital, Washington D.C., 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - McClellan Hospital, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 2003-2007 (Box 1)
  - Military men mentioned by Goulding - biographies, 2005-2008 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - biography and genealogy, 2007-2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - handwriting analysis, 2008-2008 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - New York residence and business sites, 2008-2010 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - photographs of New York residence and business sites, undated (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - life and history in Stockport, New York, 2004-2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - surgical instruments business, 2004-2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - surgical instruments illustrated on Echols web site, 2004-2008 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - notes by descendent Ed Ford, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding - notes by George Baur, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding, Jr. - notes by George Baur, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 2007-2011; Series II
  - Goulding, Warwick, 2007-2011 (Box 1)
  - Lamar, Howard, 2007-2007 (Box 1)
- Maps and Photographs, 2007-2008; Series III
  Scope and Contents
  Photographic copies of maps and photographs.
  - Maps by Tom Jonas, undated (Box 1)
  - 1844 Independence Guard photographs, 2007 (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding photographs, 2008, undated (Box 1)
  - 1849 William R. and Ann Goulding photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - 1849 Goulding family photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Warwick and Hiromi Goulding photographs, 2007- (Box 1)
  - William R. Goulding, Jr. photograph, undated (Box 1)
- Computer media
  - WR GOULDING, 2007; 2011-wa-24-0001; 1 (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Contains images of and notes on the Goulding family.